# Yaroslav Tkachenko

Director of Engineering, Platform at Bench Accounting

sapiensy@gmail.com

## Summary

I'm a polyglot Software Engineer, I love to work with DevOps tools and practices, design and build infrastructure for complex systems, work on software architecture and design, distributed systems and back-end programming (Python, Node.js, Java, Scala) with a focus on scalability and high availability.

I also have a huge experience in Web development, working knowledge of QA, Agile product/project management, functional programming.

Current areas of interest:

- Akka, Erlang/OTP and Actor systems in general
- Event sourcing and CQRS
- Microservices

Full list of things I'm interested in includes Elixir, Go, Clojure, Haskell, as well as Kafka, Cassandra and Spark.

# Experience

#### Director of Engineering, Platform at Bench Accounting

October 2015 - Present (10 months)

Working with multiple domain-oriented cross-functional teams, mostly focused on infrastructure, platform and integrations. Still an active contributor to a variety of projects (mostly Java, Scala and Node.js).

#### **Engineering Lead at Bench Accounting**

April 2014 - September 2015 (1 year 6 months)

Bench Accounting platform redesign and implementation: converting big monolith Java/Scala application to a set of microservices with Scala and Node.js using modern DevOps practices and tools.

Various responsibilities in different periods of time including:

- Leading features development
- Leading microservices stack development including back-end and infrastructure
- Software architecture and design
- DevOps/Automation
- Quality control and supervision for the Engineering team

- Tactical management for Agile processes
- Hiring
- Mentoring

### Software Engineer at Bench Accounting

September 2011 - March 2014 (2 years 7 months)

Full stack development for Bench Accounting platform and internal tools:

- Building first REST API (Java, Scala) and then using it for creating multiple SPAs (CoffeeScript, RequireJS, Backbone.js)
- Working on core services (Java) like financial platform, bookkeeper automation, reporting
- Working on 3rd party integrations (Java, Scala), including billing integration with Stripe and integrations with financial institutions
- Mentoring other developers, code reviews, etc.
- Scrum master since January 2014

#### Senior Web Developer at PureBulk, Inc.

March 2010 - July 2011 (1 year 5 months)

Big e-commerce website, Zencart and Magento platforms.

- Maintenance and additional features for the platform.
- Implemented special shipping module based on a packing optimization problem.
- Heavy front-end development using jQuery, Prototype.js and in-house JavaScript MVC framework.
- Lots of front-end and back-end loading speed / performance optimizations.

#### Web Developer at oDesk Freelancer

March 2010 - June 2011 (1 year 4 months)

I participated in multiple projects as a remote web developer:

- Stinova ltd. (http://www.stinova.com)
- Duffelup (http://duffelup.com)
- PrivacyChoice (http://www.privacychoice.org)

#### Web Developer at Aconcept

November 2009 - February 2010 (4 months)

- Implemented various websites and web applications for USA and German clients.
- Worked on internal SEO-focused services and tools.
- Led educational courses for interns, including HTML/CSS coding, PHP, JavaScript and MySQL.

#### Junior Web Developer at IA Globus

January 2007 - June 2007 (6 months)

- Was part of the team working on a Russian music social network (back-end and front-end).
- Worked on a promo website for a British football club (Football League One).
- Created a few web sites for local companies.

## Languages

Russian

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

**English** 

(Professional working proficiency)

## Skills & Expertise

**Microservices** 

**Actor systems** 

**Enterprise Integration** 

**Software Architecture** 

**DevOps** 

**Amazon Web Services (AWS)** 

**REST** 

Scala

Akka

**SBT** 

Java

**J2EE** 

**Spring** 

Hibernate

Node.js

**Python** 

Django

Flask

**JavaScript** 

CoffeeScript

HTML5

**CSS** 

Git

**MySQL** 

MongoDB

**PostgreSQL** 

**Bash** 

**Ansible** 

**Continuous Delivery** 

**Nginx** 

**ActiveMQ** 

**Apache Camel** 

**Functional Programming** 

**Agile Methodologies** 

Scrum

Kanban

**Design Patterns** 

**Test Automation** 

#### Selenium

## Education

## **Omsk State Technical University (OSTU)**

Engineer's Degree, Software Engineering and System Analysis, 2007 - 2012

## Implementing Domain-Driven Design workshop, by Vaughn Vernon

2016 - 2016

## **Introduction to Machine Learning Using Spark, Polyglot Unconference**

2015 - 2015

## Real World Programming With Haskell, Polyglot Unconference

2014 - 2014

## Certifications

#### **Functional Programming Principles in Scala**

Coursera Verified Certificates License PJF598EDUN June 2014

#### **Principles of Reactive Programming**

Coursera Verified Certificates License LPNX62XTNU May 2015

# Yaroslav Tkachenko

Director of Engineering, Platform at Bench Accounting

sapiensy@gmail.com



## 1 person has recommended Yaroslav

"Yaroslav has been an enormous asset to our company. He has given us a lot of extremely high quality work. He's not only intelligent, communicative, proactive, but Yaroslav is also made of the highest quality of moral fiber...we trust him with everything, and he has given us several awesome years of coding & development. Slava is an excellent all around human being, and any group of people would be extremely lucky to count him in their midst."

— Jared Smith, managed Yaroslav at PureBulk, Inc.

Contact Yaroslav on LinkedIn